<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Members on Hiroshima Univ. Particles and Hardon</title><link>%7B%7BBASE_URL%7D%7D/en/members/</link><description>Recent content in Members on Hiroshima Univ. Particles and Hardon</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 23:30:47 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="%7B%7BBASE_URL%7D%7D/en/members/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Visitors</title><link>%7B%7BBASE_URL%7D%7D/en/members/past/visitors/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 10:30:34 +0900</pubDate><guid>%7B%7BBASE_URL%7D%7D/en/members/past/visitors/</guid><description>&lt;!--
NOTE:
Tilte is displayed as Topic title in Home page and Listing page.
Description is displayed as Short summary in Home page.
This area up to !--more-- is displayed as Summary in listing pages linked from sidebar items.
-->
&lt;p>These are the past long-term visitors, intensive lecturers, and staff for our lab.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Career Opportunities</title><link>%7B%7BBASE_URL%7D%7D/en/members/past/career/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 15:56:53 +0900</pubDate><guid>%7B%7BBASE_URL%7D%7D/en/members/past/career/</guid><description>&lt;!--
NOTE:
Tilte is displayed as Topic title in Home page and Listing page.
Description is displayed as Short summary in Home page.
This area up to !--more-- is displayed as Summary in listing pages linked from sidebar items.
-->
&lt;p>This is a listing of different careers people have gone on after graduating from the doctoral course.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Degrees Conferred</title><link>%7B%7BBASE_URL%7D%7D/en/members/past/degrees/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 15:55:53 +0900</pubDate><guid>%7B%7BBASE_URL%7D%7D/en/members/past/degrees/</guid><description>&lt;!--
NOTE:
Tilte is displayed as Topic title in Home page and Listing page.
Description is displayed as Short summary in Home page.
This area up to !--more-- is displayed as Summary in listing pages linked from sidebar items.
-->
&lt;p>This is a listing of the thesis titles and links to the Hiroshima University Institutional Repository.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ken-Ichi Ishikawa</title><link>%7B%7BBASE_URL%7D%7D/en/members/staff/ishikawa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 09:39:35 +0900</pubDate><guid>%7B%7BBASE_URL%7D%7D/en/members/staff/ishikawa/</guid><description>Name : Ken-Ichi Ishikawa
Research Interests: Lattice QCD, Elementary particle physics
Address: Hiroshima University, Department of Physical Science, Kagamiyama 1-3-1, Higashi Hiroshima, 739-8526, Japan
Office Phone : +81-(0)824-24-7363
Office FAX : +81-(0)824-24-0717
E-mail : ishikawa[at mark]phys.sci.hiroshima-u.jp.ac
Papers : inspirehep A stencil communication sample program with double buffering using MPI-1. The two dimensional Poisson equation is solved with the Jacobi iteration algorithm. This work has been done with Issaku Kanamori and the co-design working group members for the lattice QCD applications on Post K Computer, and supported by Priority Issue 9 to be tackled by Using Post K Computer.</description></item><item><title>Professor Takuya Morozumi</title><link>%7B%7BBASE_URL%7D%7D/en/members/staff/morozumi/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 17:48:20 +0900</pubDate><guid>%7B%7BBASE_URL%7D%7D/en/members/staff/morozumi/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="research-introduction">Research Introduction&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The subject I am currently working is research into the violation of charge parity (CP) symmetry. CP symmetry is a key symmetry, and many believe that CP violation and the asymmetry of matter and antimatter in our Universe are related to each other. However, revealing the connection between the asymmetry observed on a macroscopic scale and CP violation in the microscopic world is a challenging problem. The precision of measurements of CP violations in laboratory experiments under well-controlled conditions can be improved by repeating the measurements many times. In contrast, for the CP asymmetry observed in the Universe, experiments cannot be repeated. The matter-antimatter asymmetry that is observed today was produced only one time at a certain period in the history of the Universe. Therefore, to test theoretical hypotheses, it would be necessary to return to and observe that time armed with our present knowledge based upon the laws of nature. However, since the observable Universe is limited in size and our observations lack precision, this is difficult to achieve. Considering the situation, I am currently using a working hypothesis to study how the density of the matter-antimatter asymmetry evolves with time. We are working on a simple scalar field theory which includes only a complex scalar field, and have obtained interesting results which may relate to the question of the origin of matter (See R. Hotta, T. Morozumi, and H. Takata, Phys. Rev. D90 (2014) 016008).&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>